When you are genuinely enthusiastic about something,
Quando si è genuinamente entusiasti di qualcosa,
that’s the … And this is a little preaching thing here; everybody …
quello è il... E questa qui è una piccola cosa sulla predica; tutti...
is people go, “What or how should we preach, what should we do?”
le persone chiedono: «Cosa o come dovremmo predicare, cosa dovremmo fare?».
[Preaching | Share What You Like!]
[Predicare | Condividi Ciò Che Ti Piace]
And I almost say the same thing all the time,
Ed io dico quasi sempre la stessa cosa,
although, yes—atma-jñana: we start with certain things about the soul,
benché, sì—atma-jñana: cominciamo con certe cose in merito all'anima,
transmigration— that’s true, we do that.
la trasmigrazione— è vero, facciamolo.
But, in addition to that, if you want to stay vital yourself,
Ma, in aggiunta a ciò, se vuoi mantenerti vitale,
you tell people …
dici alle persone...
‘Vital’ means ‘life’, ‘keep your vitality’, like in ‘not get bored and monoton …’
"Vitale" ossia "vita", "mantieni la tua vitalità", cioè "non essere noioso e monotono...",
“Oh, I said the same thing, over and over and over again …”
«Oh, ho detto la stessa cosa, ancora e ancora e ancora...».
If you will share what you’re appreciating, what you like …
Se condividi ciò che apprezzi, ciò che ti piace...
Just like when we eat something … And this is funny too.
Proprio come quando mangiamo qualcosa... E questo è buffo.
Like, mayavadis or impersonalists, they will say,
Come i mayavadi o impersonalisti, dicono:
“When you eat something very nice, you become silent.”
«Quando mangi qualcosa di molto buono, ti fai silenzioso».
You get it? That’s what they say.
Capito? Questo dicono.
We don’t say that. And that’s not our experience.
Noi non diciamo questo. E questa non è la nostra esperienza.
My experience is if you eat something very nice, you go like,
La mia esperienza è che se mangi qualcosa di molto buono, te ne esci tipo:
“Wow!!!”
«Wow!!!».
You know, like, “Did you have this? Did you get the sabji yet?” or,
Sapete, tipo, «Avete assaggiato questo? Avete già assaggiato il sabji?» oppure
“Did you get the sweet? You’ve got to try it!”
«Hai preso il dolce? Lo devi provare!».
Gurudev called Paramananda once, on the telephone.
Una volta Gurudev chiamò Paramanand al telefono.
Paramananda is like, driving … And it’s when Gurudev’s health is not good …
Paramananda stava guidando... Era quando Gurudev non era in buona salute...
And he gets a call from Gurudev, he’s going like, “What’s wrong?”
E riceve una chiamata da Gurudev, e chiede: «Che c'è che non va?».
And he goes, “You got to come back immediately!”
E lui risponde: «Devi tornare immediatamente!».
And he’s going, “All right, I’m coming!”
E lui: «Va bene, arrivo!».
He thinks Gurudev is like, in trouble. Healthwise.
Pensa che Gurudev abbia qualche problema di salute.
And when he gets back, he says,
E quando fa ritorno, lui dice:
“Did you taste the sweet rice that Manasa Kṛṣṇa made?
«Hai assaggiato il riso dolce che ha fatto Manasa Kṛṣṇa?».
Did you taste this? This is unbelievable!”
Lo hai provato? È incredibile!».
He called him, like, on the phone …
Lo chiamò al telefono...
He is racing back, like, you know,
Tornò di corsa, tipo, sapete,
killed the couple of people on the way … But
uccise un paio di persone per la strada... Ma
they, you know, they were run over in the service
furono investite per motivi di servizio
and got sukriti, they’re now in heaven …
ed hanno guadagnato sukriti, ora sono in paradiso...
[Laughing]
[Ride]
So when you taste something, anything, on any level,
Dunque quando assaggi qualcosa, qualsiasi cosa, a qualsiasi livello,
about Kṛṣṇa consciousness,
della coscienza di Kṛṣṇa,
that’s what you share with people … They go, “What should I say first?
è questo che condividi con le persone... Chiedono: «Cosa dovrei dire come prima cosa?
Should I start talking …”, you know.
Dovrei parlare...», avete presente.
No, no—what you like.
No, no—Quello che ti piace.
When Bon Maharaj of Italy, Bhakti Madhur Bon,
Quando il Bon Maharaj dell'Italia, Bhakti Madhur Bon,
he came to the Math …
venne alla Math...
He was actually a catholic priest previously;
Era in realtà un prete cattolico in precedenza;
which is, like, an interesting story.
e questa è una storia interessante.
So, he comes to the Math and in his first meeting with Guru Maharāj
Dunque, viene alla Math ed è al suo primo incontro con Guru Maharāj
he is telling like, “Oh, I’ve read some Bhagavad-gita …”, you know.
e dice: «Oh, ho letto la Bhagavad-gita...».
And it was interesting seeing how Guru Maharāj is dealing with someone for the first time,
Ed era interessante vedere come Guru Maharāj si rapportava con qualcuno per la prima volta,
and he goes, “Oh, you’ve read Bhagavad-gita …”
e dice: «Oh, hai letto la Bhagavad-gita...».
He goes, “Which part did you like?”
E dice: «Quale parte ti è piaciuta?».
That’s what he said to him,
Questo gli disse:
“Which part of the book did you like?”
«Quale parte del libro ti è piaciuta?».
And this is how he scored a lot of points quickly,
Ed è così che guadagnò un sacco di punti velocemente,
he said, you know, he is talking like-a ‘deeze’ [this], because have a little bit of Italian accent,
disse, sapete, parlava tipo "deeze" [this], perché aveva un po' di accento italiano,
and a little from a Dante place, you know …
ed un po' come Dante, sapete...
He says, “I like the part, where He says, ‘Surrender everything to Me, become My devotee.
Dice: «Mi piace la parte dove Egli dice "abbandona qualsiasi cosa a Me, diventa mio devoto.
Give up everything and become My devotee.’”
Abbandona tutto e diventa mio devoto».
And like, you could hear like a bell goes, “Ding!”, you know, like
E fu come sentire una campanella, "Ding!"
and Guru Maharaj is like, “Bless you, my child!”
e Guru Maharaj: «Sii benedetto, figlio mio!».
So it’s like, in the eighteenth chapter, when Krishna says,
Dunque, è nel diciottesimo paragrafo, quando Krishna dice:
“Give up everything and surrender to Me”, he goes, “I really like that part.”
«Abbandona tutto ed arrenditi a Me», dice: «Mi piace davvero quella parte».
So Guru Maharaj is saying, “Hmm, interesting man.”
Allora Guru Maharaj dice: «Hmm, persona interessante».